<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Personal on Staring Blankly at a Screen</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/personal/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Personal on Staring Blankly at a Screen</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <copyright>© 2025 Aaron Sachs. All rights reserved.</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 10:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>How Homebrewing Saved Me from Burnout</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/how-homebrewing-saved-me-from-burnout/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/how-homebrewing-saved-me-from-burnout/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Working in tech can be all-consuming. The constant learning, the on-call rotations, the endless stream of new technologies - it&amp;rsquo;s exhilarating but exhausting. A few years ago, I found myself staring at screens from dawn to dusk, losing touch with the physical world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s when I discovered homebrewing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-perfect-antidote&#34;&gt;The Perfect Antidote
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Homebrewing offered everything that my tech job didn&amp;rsquo;t:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tangible results&lt;/strong&gt;: You can hold a bottle of beer you made&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Patience required&lt;/strong&gt;: Good beer takes weeks, not microseconds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Science meets art&lt;/strong&gt;: Precision matters, but so does creativity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community&lt;/strong&gt;: Local homebrew clubs are full of passionate, helpful people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Failure is okay&lt;/strong&gt;: A bad batch teaches you more than a perfect one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lessons-learned&#34;&gt;Lessons Learned
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The brewing process taught me valuable lessons that applied back to my tech work:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Documentation matters&lt;/strong&gt;: Recipe notes are like code comments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Iteration is key&lt;/strong&gt;: Each batch builds on the last&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simplicity often wins&lt;/strong&gt;: The best beers aren&amp;rsquo;t always the most complex&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Share your work&lt;/strong&gt;: Getting feedback makes you better&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;finding-your-balance&#34;&gt;Finding Your Balance
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t need to take up homebrewing specifically. Find something that gets you away from the keyboard, engages different parts of your brain, and produces something real. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s woodworking, gardening, cooking, or playing music - having a physical creative outlet can save you from digital burnout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next time you&amp;rsquo;re debugging code at 2 AM, remember: there&amp;rsquo;s a world beyond the screen, and it&amp;rsquo;s worth exploring.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
