<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Homebrewing on Staring Blankly at a Screen</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/homebrewing/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Homebrewing on Staring Blankly at a Screen</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <copyright>© 2025 Aaron Sachs. All rights reserved.</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 16:48:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/homebrewing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>How I Homebrew</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/archive/how-i-homebrew/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 16:48:02 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/archive/how-i-homebrew/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve met quite a few homebrewers over the years and have learned tons from them. One of the things I always like asking about it their setup and getting to know what they use on brew day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I figured it&amp;rsquo;s time for me to do a HIB (How I Homebrew) post and let you know what I started brewing on, and where I&amp;rsquo;ve progressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;for-starters&#34;&gt;For Starters
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I first started brewing, I started on a hand-me-down &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.mrbeer.com/beer-making-kits/craft-beer-kits&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Mr. Beer&lt;/a&gt; kit that had solidified LME with it. I went to Walmart and picked up a cheap 3 gallon aluminum kettle, and brewed my first beer (an ESB).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wasn&amp;rsquo;t long before I realized that I wantd to brew larger batches and to do that, I&amp;rsquo;d need to upgrade. I upgraded my fermentation vessel (the Mr. Beer LBK) first. This was great, but I was essentially making extract in my undersized brew kettle, which I upgraded next. This began a long process of creating the piecemeal setup that I currently have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;currently-using&#34;&gt;Currently Using&amp;hellip;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the fun part for me. I&amp;rsquo;ll skip over all the sequential upgrades, and get to the good stuff. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;m currently using, and am quite happy with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 x &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.heb.com/product-detail/imusa-aluminum-tamale-steamer/861634&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;8gal Tamale Steamers&lt;/a&gt; (boil kettle &amp;amp; HLT)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.austinhomebrew.com/Igloo-Cooler-Mash-Tun-with-False-Bottom--10-Gallon_p_5722.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Igloo mash tun&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some copper tubing from Home Depot (immersion chiller)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2x PVC buckets (primary fermenters)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2x 6gal glass carboys (secondary fermenters)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bayou Classic w/ 6&amp;quot; burner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But wait! There&amp;rsquo;s more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve got some incoming upgrades, namely a 10&amp;quot; burner for the Bayou Classic stand, and a &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://jadedbrewing.com/collections/frontpage/products/the-hydra&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Jaded Brewing Hydra&lt;/a&gt;! I&amp;rsquo;m hoping these will shorten my brew day. Not that I &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; them to be short, but I&amp;rsquo;m hoping for them to be a bit more efficient. Anywho, that&amp;rsquo;s the current setup!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>How Homebrewing Saved Me from Burnout</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/how-homebrewing-saved-me-from-burnout/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/how-homebrewing-saved-me-from-burnout/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Working in tech can be all-consuming. The constant learning, the on-call rotations, the endless stream of new technologies - it&amp;rsquo;s exhilarating but exhausting. A few years ago, I found myself staring at screens from dawn to dusk, losing touch with the physical world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s when I discovered homebrewing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-perfect-antidote&#34;&gt;The Perfect Antidote
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Homebrewing offered everything that my tech job didn&amp;rsquo;t:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tangible results&lt;/strong&gt;: You can hold a bottle of beer you made&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Patience required&lt;/strong&gt;: Good beer takes weeks, not microseconds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Science meets art&lt;/strong&gt;: Precision matters, but so does creativity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community&lt;/strong&gt;: Local homebrew clubs are full of passionate, helpful people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Failure is okay&lt;/strong&gt;: A bad batch teaches you more than a perfect one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lessons-learned&#34;&gt;Lessons Learned
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The brewing process taught me valuable lessons that applied back to my tech work:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Documentation matters&lt;/strong&gt;: Recipe notes are like code comments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Iteration is key&lt;/strong&gt;: Each batch builds on the last&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simplicity often wins&lt;/strong&gt;: The best beers aren&amp;rsquo;t always the most complex&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Share your work&lt;/strong&gt;: Getting feedback makes you better&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;finding-your-balance&#34;&gt;Finding Your Balance
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t need to take up homebrewing specifically. Find something that gets you away from the keyboard, engages different parts of your brain, and produces something real. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s woodworking, gardening, cooking, or playing music - having a physical creative outlet can save you from digital burnout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next time you&amp;rsquo;re debugging code at 2 AM, remember: there&amp;rsquo;s a world beyond the screen, and it&amp;rsquo;s worth exploring.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Moving to Kegging my Homebrew</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/archive/moving-to-kegging/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 17:49:16 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/archive/moving-to-kegging/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve posted previously about &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://aaron.sachs.blog/how-homebrewing-saved-me-from-burnout/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;homebrewing&lt;/a&gt; and have been brewing for almost three years now. Back in April, I took to destroying a perfectly good mini fridge to turn it into a kegerator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/IMG_20170403_105320.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;IMG_20170403_105320&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As any homebrewer can tell you, bottling is a pain in the ass. The delabling (if you&amp;rsquo;re reusing bottles), the santization, and the bottle carbonization makes for a rather long and laborious process. Because I&amp;rsquo;d finally had it with bottling, I decided that kegging would be a wiser choice since:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Less time would be spent on bottling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Carbonization would be better controlled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For most ales, production time would be cut by a week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, my assumptions have proven to be true. So let&amp;rsquo;s walk through what it took to make the kegerator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-build&#34;&gt;The Build
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I started off with the following hardware:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Whirlpool-Stainless-Compact-Refrigerator-Fridge/dp/B00XQLQXMY&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Whirlpool 4.3 cu ft mini fridge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.beveragefactory.com/draftbeer/towers/doublefaucet/D4743DT___6843.shtml&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Chrome plated dual faucet tower&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.midwestsupplies.com/draft-brewer-flex-keg-system&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Draft Brewer Flex Keg System&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.austinhomebrew.com/Aluminum-CO2-Tank--5-lb_p_4693.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Aluminum CO2 Tank - 5 lb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.beveragefactory.com/draftbeer/driptray/cutout/kegco-surface-mount-drip-tray-seco1610.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Surface Mount Drip Tray&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I won&amp;rsquo;t go through the whole process of assembling, since the post over at &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://missionarybrewer.wordpress.com/how-to-build-your-own-kegerator/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;missionarybrewer&lt;/a&gt; (which my build was largely based on) covers the steps more than sufficiently. I will mention a few gotchas for the particular fridge I used:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are coolant lines running over in the upper rear left corner. DON&amp;rsquo;T drill back there&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The 4.3 cu ft size is just a hair too small for both kegs to fit comfortably. I ended up using a multitool to carve out the front of the door, as well as the molding for holding the shelves so that the kegs would fit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, some pics of the kegerator:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/IMG_20170403_162917.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;IMG_20170403_162917&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/IMG_20170403_193658.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;IMG_20170403_193658&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/IMG_20170403_193702.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;IMG_20170403_193702&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/IMG_20170403_193658-1.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;IMG_20170403_193658-1&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/IMG_20170403_193706.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;IMG_20170403_193706&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/IMG_20170403_193711.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;IMG_20170403_193711&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/IMG_20170403_231824.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;IMG_20170403_231824&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve got any questions, feel free to reach out and let me know!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>How Homebrewing Saved Me from Burnout</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/archive/how-homebrewing-saved-me-from-burnout/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2016 00:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/archive/how-homebrewing-saved-me-from-burnout/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s weird to say that beer saved me from depression. Let&amp;rsquo;s face it, it&amp;rsquo;s not exactly the most common thing for someone to claim as having a positive impact on one&amp;rsquo;s life. But beer saved me, in a weird sort of way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last winter, I was miserable. My wife saw it, my coworkers saw it, and after many conversations that highlighted my incessant complaining about my former employer, I finally admitted that I was in fact, a bit of a mess. My symptoms included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being a bit of an ass to my wife, whom I love fiercely&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being a outright ass to some of my customers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complaining about the lack of necessary change occurring in my department&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And generally complaining about anything I could find a reason to complain about&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, I was bitter, overly critical, and no one wanted to be around me&amp;hellip;including me. I&amp;rsquo;d woken up several times during the winter months and thought, &amp;ldquo;Not again. I can&amp;rsquo;t do another day of this. Why in the hell did I move 1,100 miles for this?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s when one of my dearest friends and mentors suggested that I take up a hobby. He and I&amp;rsquo;d been talking over Slack and he asked me, &amp;ldquo;Do you have any hobbies?&amp;rdquo; Dumbstruck, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t recall having anything to do during my free time other than study for certifications and try and bone up on all things *NIX-y. That night, I decided that I was going to take a week and learn how to homebrew. That was the best decision for my mental health that I&amp;rsquo;d made in a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d mentioned to a coworker that I was going to take some time to homebrew. He generously gave me his kit, noting that he wasn&amp;rsquo;t using it. After a month, I had a passable &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.beeradvocate.com/beer/style/66/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;ESB&lt;/a&gt;. Mind you, it was a bit watery, but it was by no means terrible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In that watered-down, bubbly bit of brew, I found a hobby. I found something that would keep me from being completely burnt out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m particularly interested in why brewing staved off the burnout. After all, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t that I chose brewing as a hobby with the express purpose of keeping my sanity. I had chosen homebrewing on a whim, namely because I like good beer and wanted to make my own &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; beer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wasn&amp;rsquo;t until Christmas that my mentor hit on something in a &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://sysadvent.blogspot.com/2015/12/day-8-be-better-engineer-dont-do.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;SysAdvent&lt;/a&gt; post that he wrote. To quote him: &amp;ldquo;Brewing beer is a mixture of being methodical, something that is near and dear to all our hearts, and art.&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;d found a medium of expression that allowed me to still be methodical (something that was required in solving the types of problems a systems administrator solves), and be creative&amp;hellip;the element that was missing from day-to-day duties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.16personalities.com/intp-personality&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;INTP&lt;/a&gt;, I need space to create. Relentless break-fixing is something I&amp;rsquo;ve since discovered contributes to a regular cycle of burnout for me. If I&amp;rsquo;m stuck in that constant cycle, I&amp;rsquo;ll inevitably start becoming a bit of an ass again. Thankfully, I&amp;rsquo;ve got a few hobbies now, and one that I&amp;rsquo;ve found that I love doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: If you&amp;rsquo;re struggling with burnout, head over to &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://burnout.io&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;burnout.io&lt;/a&gt;. The site has a great list of ways that you can mitigate burnout.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
